Benjamin Franklin University 114
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Benjamin Franklin University Collection
1925-1964
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Benjamin Franklin University (Washington, D.C.)
114
0.5 Linear feet
1 Boxes
Arrangement
Collection arranged without series.
Biographical / Historical
The Benjamin Franklin University was founded in 1925 tas a successor to Pace Institute. The University was grounded in Benjamin Franklin's doctrine of thrift and self-reliance and was aimed at students who worked full-time. After completing three years of courses in accountancy and business administration students were eligible to earn a bachelor's degree in commercial science. The University also offered master's degrees in commercial science. The University closed in August 1987 after the District's accountancy board introduced new regulations for degrees which would require expanded liberal arts courses and additional full-time faculty members. The University merged with George Washington University, School of Business and Public Management. Although the University was open to female students from its founding, black students were barred from enrolling until 1964. By its closing in 1987 the University had graduated approximately 8,000 students. Those students enrolled when the University closed were granted reduced tuition at George Washington University to complete their degrees.
Custodial History
Related Materials
Benjamin Franklin Univeristy records, RG0116, George Washington University: https://searcharchives.library.gwu.edu/repositories/2/resources/666
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of yearbooks and alumni and student books.
Education, higher; Yearbooks; College students
- Series 1
  - Yearbook, 1925-1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Yearbook, 1926-1927 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yearbook, 1927-1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Yearbook, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Yearbook, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Yearbook, 1930-1931 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Yearbook, 1931-1932 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yearbook, 1932-1933 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Yearbook, 1934-1935 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Yearbook, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Yearbook, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Yearbook, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Yearbook, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Yearbook, 1941-1942 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Yearbook, 1942-1943 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Yearbook, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Yearbook, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Yearbook, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Yearbook, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Yearbook, 1948-1949 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Yearbook, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Yearbook, 1955-1956 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Yearbook, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Yearbook, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Yearbook, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Alumni and Student Books, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Alumni and Student Books, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Alumni and Student Books, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Alumni and Student Books, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 29)